leatherology.com 2019-06-03

# Privacy Policy | Leatherology

This Privacy Policy explains how information about you is collected, used and disclosed by DC International, Inc., D/B/A Leatherology.com (“Leatherology”). This Privacy Policy applies to the information we collect about you when you use our website (“Service”) and other online products or otherwise interact with us. By using our website, or sharing your contact information with us, you accept and consent to the practices described in this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review this Policy whenever you access the Services or otherwise interact with us to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

## Types of Information Collected

**Information you provide to us:**

When you use our Service, we collect information you provide directly to us to identify you. For example, we collect information when you create an account, make a purchase, or otherwise communicate with us. The types of information we may collect include your name, email address, billing and shipping address, phone number, payment information, site reviews you write and any other information you choose to provide. We may also maintain a record of your product purchases. Please note that we do not store credit or debit card numbers, but you may elect for our payment processor to store your card information on your behalf. 

Please note that if you submit content to a public area of the site (user reviews, user generated content and photos, etc.), such content will be considered “public” and will not be subject to the privacy protections set forth herein.

**Usage data:**

We may also collect information from you in regards to how our Service is accessed and used ("Usage Data"). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, the location of your device, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

**Tracking & Cookie Data**

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information. Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device that help us improve our Services. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service. Examples of Cookies we use include:

  * **Session Cookies.** We use Session Cookies to operate our website.
  * **Preference Cookies.** We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
  * **Security Cookies.** We use Security Cookies for security purposes.

**Information from other sources:**

If you access any of our websites or mobile applications with your log-in credentials from a social networking site (e.g., Facebook or Instagram) or if you otherwise agree to associate your account with us with a social networking site, we may receive personal information about you from such social networking site, in accordance with the terms of use and privacy policy of the social networking site. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via website.

## Use of information

We use the information we collect from you for various purposes, including:

  * To provide, maintain and improve our Services
  * To process your transaction, send you transactional emails and notices related to your order, and to deliver the products and services you request.
  * To notify you about changes to our Service
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to
  * To provide customer care and support
  * To provide analysis or valuable information so that we can improve the Service
  * To monitor the usage of the Service
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues and prevent potentially illegal activities
  * To communicate with you about products, services, and promotions that may be of interest to you
  * To personalize advertisements, content or features that match your profile or interests

## Sharing of information and Data

We may share information about you as follows, or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

  * With Vendors, consultants and other third-party service providers we trust who need access to such information to carry out work on our behalf, and to perform Service-related services to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used. These third-parties have access your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.
  * With other users on our website if you choose to post a public review and include personal information;
  * In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company;
  * Between and among DC International-owned family of brands, affiliates, subsidiaries and other companies under common control and ownership.
  * In response to a request for information if we believe disclosure is in accordance with, or required by, any applicable law, regulation or legal process; including: 
    * To comply with a legal obligation
    * To protect and defend the rights or property of DC International
    * To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
    * To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public

Your information, including Personal Data, may also be transferred to and maintained on computers outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction. If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to United States and process it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

## Advertising and Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers such as Google Analytics to monitor and analyze the use of our Service and serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet. These entities may use cookies, web beacons, device identifiers and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Services and other websites and online services, including your IP address, web browser, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked and conversion information. This information may be used by us to analyze and track data and deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on our Services and other websites and online services.

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. 

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity. For more information on how Google uses your data when you use its partner sites or apps, visit the [Google Partner Sites Privacy & Terms web page](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the [Google Privacy & Terms web page](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). 

## Security of Data

We take security seriously and make every effort to protect your personal information. When you purchase something from our Website, we use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software to guard the information you provide us. SSL encrypts certain purchasing information you input. We do not store credit card information on any computers, but rather use tokenization process to ensure your purchase is secured.

Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your information, to the extent permitted by law, we do not guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to or from our web sites, and you do so at your own risk. We do not accept liability for unintentional disclosure.

By using the Site or providing Personal Information to us, you agree that we may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of the Site. If we learn of a security system’s breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically or via mail. 

## Your Choices

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies. Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our Services. 

You may opt out of receiving marketing emails from Leatherology by following the instructions to unsubscribe, that are listed in the emails. If you opt-out of promotional emails, we may still need to send you non-promotional emails, such as ones confirming your purchase transactions. Please note that requests to remove your email from our email marketing list may take up to a week to take effect.

You may opt out of receiving direct mail pieces from Leatherology by contacting info@leatherology.com and asking to be removed from our catalog list. Please note that it may take up to 8-12 weeks to remove your name from our direct mail list and stop receiving catalogs, as print mailers are sent to print far in advance of their in-home dates.

## Children’s Privacy

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

## Links to Other Sites

From time to time, our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that third-party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit. We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third-party sites or services.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will update the effective date listed for the Policy. You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. The new Policy will apply to all current and past users of our web sites and will replace any prior policies that are inconsistent. Your continued use of our web sites or other services constitutes your acceptance of the practices described in the revised Privacy Policy.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [info@leatherology.com](mailto:security@leatherology.com). 

Privacy Policy Effective Date: October 12th, 2018
